<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY version "2.4.0">
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect2 id="rnepiphany">
  <title>Epiphany</title>
  <para>With <application>Epiphany</application>, GNOME &version; brings a
  clean and simple browser to the free software desktop based on Mozilla, the
  most standards-compliant rendering widget available.
<!--    
    <figure id="rnepiphanyscreenshot"> 
        <title>Epiphany</title> 
        <screenshot> 
        <mediaobject> 
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;MultiLoad_applet.png"
			format="PNG"/> 
          </imageobject>
 	  <textobject> 
 	    <phrase>Epiphany Web Browser
            </phrase> 
          </textobject> 
        </mediaobject> 
	</screenshot> 
      </figure> 
-->
  </para>
  <para>
    Epiphany uses the simplest interface possible for a browser. Simple does not
    necessarily mean less powerful. Its design is based on the belief that
    commonly used browsers of today are too big, buggy, and bloated. Epiphany
    addresses simplicity with a small browser designed for the web &mdash; not
    mail, newsgroups, file management, instant messaging or coffee making.
</para>
  <para>
    Epiphany also address simplicity with modularity to make a light and
    powerful application. If something can be implemented using external
    applications or components, Epiphany's developers use it rather than wasting
    resources in the web browser. Integration is achieved with CORBA, Bonobo, and
    the command line.
  </para>
  <para>
    The introduction of non-standard features in browsers could make it
    difficult or impossible to use alternative products like Epiphany if
    developers embrace them. Alternative (standards complying) browsers could
    not be able to fully access web sites making use of these features. The
    success of non-standard features can ultimately lead to forcing one browser,
    on one platform to dominate the market.
  </para>
  <para>
    Standards compliance ensures the freedom of choice. Epiphany aims to achieve
    this. 
  </para>
</sect2>