<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>
<sect2 id="rna11y">
  <title>Accessibility</title>
  <para>Support for people with disabilities has been a key focus for GNOME, so successive releases have included increasing
  support for accessibility. GNOME &version; improves this framework, and its tools, to create a better experience for
  existing users, and to make the desktop available to new groups of users.</para>
  

  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-applet">
  <title>Keyboard Accessibility Status</title>

  <para>As mentioned in the accessibility section, the new Keyboard Accessibility Status gives quick access to the Accessibility
  control panel, and gives visual feedback when using the sticky-keys feature. The sticky-keys feature allows people with limited
  mobility to press modifier keys, such as shift, in sequence instead of simultaneously.  TODO: Remove the duplication?

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-accessibility-applet">
    <title>Keyboard Indicator</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;panel-applet-accessibility.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The Keyboard Accessibility Status applet, showing that the Shift and Control keys have been pressed.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  </para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-gnopernicus">
  <title>Screen Reader and Magnifier</title>

  <para>The Gnopernicus screen reader and magnifier has some new features in GNOME &version;.

  TODO: rewrite this based on email asking for explanation: For instance, the magnifier can
  now track the mouse and focus in either proportional, centered or push modes. The crosshair is rather useful for users with specific visual disabilities.

  Blind users will appreciate the &quot;watch any widget&quot; feature as well as the &quot;describe my surroundings&quot;
  feature. A very versatile presentation scheme based on role events and devices exist, and it would fulfill the most
  sophisticated needs, including support for multi-layered numerical keypad control.
  </para>

  </sect3>


  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-dasher">
  <title>Dasher</title>

  <para>Dasher is a predictive input system that should be particularly useful to people with severe disabilities.  At the moment, it
  allows text entry, but future versions should allow complete control of the desktop.

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-accessibility">
    <title>Dasher</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;accessibility-dasherTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Dasher.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  </para>

  </sect3>
</sect2>
