<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>
<sect2 id="rna11y">
  <title>Accessibility</title>
  <para>Support for people with disabilities has been a key focus for GNOME, so successive releases have included increasing
  support for accessibility. GNOME &version; improves this framework, and its tools, to create a better experience for
  existing users, and to make the desktop available to new groups of users.</para>
  

  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-applet">
  <title>Keyboard Accessibility Status</title>

  <para>The new Keyboard Accessibility Status panel applet gives quick access to the Accessibility control panel, and provides
  visual feedback when using the sticky-keys feature. The sticky-keys feature allows people with limited mobility to press
  modifier keys, such as shift, in sequence instead of simultaneously.

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-accessibility">
    <title>Keyboard Indicator</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;panel-applet-accessibility.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The Keyboard Accessibility Status applet,
      showing that the Shift and Control keys are latched.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  </para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-gnopernicus">
  <title>Screen Reader and Magnifier</title>

  <para>The Gnopernicus screen reader and magnifier has some new features in GNOME &version;, based on user needs.

  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>The &quot;watch any widget&quot; feature allows blind user to monitor changes to any part of the user interface. For
  instance, blind users can track changes to a message field, while entering text in another.</para></listitem>

  <listitem><para>The &quot;describe my surroundings&quot; feature gives blind users information about the context of
  the currently focused UI component, via speech or Braille.</para></listitem>

  <listitem><para>When used as an on-screen magnifier, Gnopernicus now gives users even more control over tracking and
  cursor presentation.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  </para>

  </sect3>


  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-gok">
  <title>On-Screen Keyboard</title>

  <para>GOK provides a suite of adaptive onscreen keyboards which dynamically respond to the user's working context, for
  users who cannot use a standard keyboard. The onscreen keyboard in GNOME &version; includes many improvements for
  non-English language users, including full localization of the standard GOK &quot;prebuilt&quot; keyboards, and full
  emulation of non-Latin physical keyboards.


  </para>

  <para>Other improvements include:

  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Detection of changes to the keyboard layout via the Keyboard Indicator applet.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Support for multi-group keyboards.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Greatly enhanced &quot;UI Grab&quot; features, allowing users to directly interact with more
  kinds of application UI elements than ever before, including applications like OpenOffice.org 1.1 and Epiphany/Mozilla.</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Improved stability. It restarts automatically if a critical error is detected.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  </para>

  </sect3>


  <sect3 id="rna11y-accessibility-dasher">
  <title>Dasher</title>

  <para>Dasher is an innovative predictive input system that should be particularly useful to people with severe motor disabilities.
  At the moment, it is primarily used for text entry, but it offers an alternative way to interact with user interface
  controls as well. It also is useful on small devices such as PDAs, to allow more efficient text entry without a keyboard.

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-accessibility-dasher">
    <title>Dasher</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;dasher.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>Dasher.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  </para>

  </sect3>
</sect2>
