<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.4">
]>
<sect2 id="rna11y">
  <title>Accessibility</title>
  <para>GNOME &version; includes major advances in accessible free software on
  the desktop with the first editions of the Gnopernicus screen reader/magnifier
  and the GOK dynamic on-screen keyboard.  Support for people with disabilities
  has been a key goal and focus of the GNOME 2 desktop platform, and successive
  releases have included increasing support for accessibility.  With &version;,
  users will be able to evaluate GNOME with assistive technolgies.</para>
  <para>The editions of Gnopernicus and GOK that will be part of GNOME 2.4 are
  well along in their development cycle; however the GNOME accessibility
  community &mdash; and specifically BAUM and the University of Toronto Adaptive
  Technology Resource Centre who are the maintainers of these projects &mdash;
  feel that Gnopernicus and GOK need further testing and development before they
  are ready for production use by people with disabilities. By including
  Gnopernicus and GOK in GNOME 2.4 we will make it easy for a large audience to
  explore these assistive technologies, and provide feedback to their
  developers.  Essentially this is a large, public beta test of the GNOME
  desktop assistive technologies.</para>
  <sect3 id="rngnopernicus">
    <title>Gnopernicus</title>
    <para>
    Gnopernicus is an open source screen reader/magnifier that enables users
      with limited vision, or no vision, to use the GNOME 2 desktop and GNOME
      applications effectively. By providing automated focus tracking and full
      screen magnification, Gnopernicus aids low-vision GNOME users, and its
      screen reader features will allow low-vision and blind users to access a
      large range of applications via speech and braille output.

    <figure id="rngnopernicusscreenshot"> 
        <title>Gnopernicus</title> 
        <screenshot> 
        <mediaobject> 
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;gnopernicus.png"
			format="PNG"/> 
          </imageobject>
 	  <textobject> 
 	    <phrase>Gnopernicus Reader/Magnifier
            </phrase> 
          </textobject> 
        </mediaobject> 
	</screenshot> 
      </figure> 

      <ulink url="http://www.baum.de/">BAUM Retec AG</ulink> is guiding
 	    Gnopernicus development, and is also the principal author and
 	    project maintainer.  BAUM has been developing screen reading and
 	    magnification software, as well as other software and hardware
 	    products for the blind, for over 20 years. More information about
 	    Gnopernicus
 	    can be found at <ulink
	url="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gap/AT/Gnopernicus">http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gap/AT/Gnopernicus</ulink>.
    </para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3 id="rnGOK">
    <title>GOK Dynamic On-Screen Keyboard</title>
    <para>
      GOK is a dynamic on-screen keyboard that enables users to control their
      computer without having to rely on a standard keyboard or mouse.
      Supporting the majority of single-switch devices already on the market,
      GOK allows users with limited voluntary movement to completely control and
      interact with their GNOME 2 desktop via one or more  alternative input
      devices, choosing from a wide range of input techniques and
      configurations.  These input methods may be controlled by actions such as
      blowing and sipping to activate a pneumatic switch, an eye blink and/or
      directed gaze with an eye tracking system, head movement, muscle
      contractions, or limb movements.
    
    <figure id="rngokscreenshot"> 
        <title>GOK</title> 
        <screenshot> 
        <mediaobject> 
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;gok.png"
			format="PNG"/> 
          </imageobject>
 	  <textobject> 
 	    <phrase>GOK On-Screen Keyboard
            </phrase> 
          </textobject> 
        </mediaobject> 
	</screenshot> 
      </figure> 

    </para>
    <para>
      Using innovative dynamic keyboard strategies, and leveraging the built-in
      accessibility framework of GNOME 2, GOK makes desktop and application
      control and interaction tremendously more efficient for users with severe
      physical impairments.  GOK directly presents on the dynamic keyboard the
      users' menu options, toolbar choices, and text manipulation commands,
      thereby saving the user the time and frustration of having to enter
      lengthy series of keyboard sequences to invoke those commands.  GOK also
      includes a word completion dictionary to speed text entry. 
    </para>
    <para>
      The <ulink url="http://atrc.utoronto.ca/">Adaptive Technology Resource
      Centre</ulink> is guiding GOK development, and is also the principal
      author and project maintainer. The University of Toronto's ATRC research
      and development lab brings strong leadership to the project with expertise
      in alternative input devices and software, and also a sincere passion
      regarding accessibility issues. The team has already produced a
      full-featured onscreen keyboard for another platform.
    </para>
    <para>
      More information about GOK can be found at <ulink
	url="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gap/AT/GOK">http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gap/AT/GOK</ulink>
      and at <ulink url="http://www.gok.ca">http://www.gok.ca</ulink>.
    </para>
  </sect3>
</sect2>
