<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>
<sect2 id="rndesktop">

    <title>Desktop</title>
    <para>  </para>

    <sect3 id="rnnautilus"><title>The File Manager</title>
    <para>
    Nautilus, the GNOME file manager has several significant improvements in GNOME &version;;. In particular, it now has a simpler
    and more intuitive user interface, and is very responsive. This should make users feel more comfortable and productive.
    </para>

    <para>This new &quot;spatial&quot; user interface presents just one window for each folder, and remembers their location
    and size. The user can then think of the window as being the folder. When the user opens a folder again, it will appear just
    as it did before, so that the user can recognise it. And if it is already open, then it will just be brought to the front.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus-spatial">
      <title>Simplified file management - the window is the folder</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;nautilus-spatialTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Spatial Nautilus</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
       </screenshot>
     </figure>

    <para>Continued use should show that a great deal of thought has gone into this new user interface, though at first you might
    notice only that new folders are opened in new windows instead of changing the existing window. As you navigate to a folder,
    you might find that there are too many folders open on your screen. You can:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Hold down the shift key when double-clicking, or double-click the middle mouse button. This closes the current folder when opening the new folder.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Choose &quot;Close Parent Folders&quot; from the File menu, or press Shift-Control-W.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Choose &quot;Open Location&quot; from the File menu, or press Control-L.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <para>The parent-folders button shows the folder's full patch, and lets you quickly open one of the parent folders. You can find this button at the bottom-left of the folder window.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus-parentfolders">
      <title>The parent-folders button</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;nautilus-parentfoldersTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Parent Folders</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
       </screenshot>
     </figure>

    </para>

    <para>Because some users are more familiar with the previous &quot;browse&quot; user interface, this is still available.</para>

    <para>The organisation of the file system and network have been reorganized into the top-level &quot;Computer&quot; location.
    This is where you can find your CD Rom and floppy drives and your hard disk's file system. This is also where you will see
    your network drives, because you can now mount Windows SMB servers, and ftp, sftp (ssh) and NFS locations here.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus-computer">
      <title>The Computer location</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;nautilus-computerTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>Computer</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
       </screenshot>
     </figure>

     <para>This is also where you will see your network drives, because you can now mount Windows SMB servers, and ftp, sftp (ssh),
     or WebDAV locations here. For instance, you can use this to change the files on your website as if they were
     in a local folder. And, in GNOME &version; you no longer need to repeatedly enter your password for network servers.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus-sftp">
      <title>A network drive</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;nautilus-sftpTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>An sftp location.</phrase></textobject>
          </mediaobject>
       </screenshot>
     </figure>
    
     <para>Other new file manager features include:
     <itemizedlist>
       <listitem><para>Complete keyboard navigation, so more experienced users can work even more efficiently.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>Type the first letters of a file to quickly select it.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>User-definable templates to easily create new documents by copying existing empty documents.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>Emblem support for list views, with a better treeview in the sidebar.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>The CD burner has better burn speed detection</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>New plug-ins system for developers.</para></listitem>
     </itemizedlist>
     </para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rngeneral">
    <title>General</title>
    
    <para>GNOME &version; and GNOME applications benefit from improvements in the user interface toolkit. Most
    importantly, you will notice an improved file selection dialog box when opening or saving files. This shows
    the same filessytem icons as you see in the &quot;Computer&quot; location on your desktop, and can remember
    bookmarks for your favourite locations, so you can quickly get to your files.</para>

    <para>Other basic improvements include
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>An improved Combo box, to choose an item from a list.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Performance improvements when showing trees of items.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>TODO</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </sect3>
    

  <sect3 id="rncontrolpanel">
    <title>Control Panel</title>

    <para>GNOME &version; makes it easier to use multiple keyboard layouts. For instance, you might choose to press both
    shift keys together to change from a U.S. English keyboard layout to a Russian keyboard layout, and then back again, to
    enter one russian word in the middle of an english sentence. This is particularly useful to the millions of people in
    the world who regularly communicate in more than one language.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-keyboardlayouts">
      <title>Keyboard Preferences - Layouts</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;controlpanel-keyboardlayoutsTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Layouts tab, in the Keyboard Preferences control panel.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </para>

    <para>The Keyboard Indicator panel applet shows the current keyboard layout and lets you choose another,
    without using the keyboard shortcut.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-keyboardindicator">
      <title>Keyboard Indicator</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;panel-applet-keyboardindicatorTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Keyboard Indicator panel applet.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </para>
     
    <para>GNOME &version; also integrates the multimedia keys into the regular Keyboard
    Shortcuts control panel, making it easy to use your keyboard's special keys to change
    volume or control music or video applications. This functionality was previously in the Acme utility.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-multimediakeys">
     <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
       <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
           <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;controlpanel-keyboardshortcutsTODO.png" format="PNG"/>
           </imageobject>
           <textobject><phrase>The Keyboard Shortcuts control panel.</phrase></textobject>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
     </para>

     
  </sect3>
</sect2>
