<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>
<sect2 id="rnlockdown">
  <title>Lockdown</title>
    
  <para>GNOME &version; allows system administrators to restrict certain functionality, so that users have a more controlled
  environment. This is particularly useful in very tightly-controlled deployments, such as call centers or internet cafes.
  When the system administrator has disabled features they will be visibly greyed-out rather than failing when used.</para>
   
  <para>For instance, the GNOME panel allows system administrators to
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Completely prevent any changes to the panel.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Prevent certain applets from being added.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Prevent certain actions, such as log out and shut down.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Prevent access to the command-line.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <para>The web browser allows system administrators to
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Disable the ability to type in a URL instead of using bookmarks and links.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Disable content from specified unsafe protocols, such as ftp.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Disable the editing of bookmarks and toolbars.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Disable the Back button, and all history.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Hide the menu, toolbar, or statusbar by default.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Disable JavaScript's control over window chrome.</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  </para>

  <para>GnomeMeeting allows system administrators to specify that calls may only be routed through one particular gatekeeper.
  </para>

  <para>These lockdown options can be configured by the system administrator with the gconf editor, and then distributed throughout the network.
  
  <figure id="rnscreenshot-gconfeditor-lockdown">
  <title>Lockdown configuration</title>
    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;lockdownTODO.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The configuration editor, showing a lockdown item.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>
  </para>

</sect2>
