<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnplatform">
  <title>Platform Improvements</title>
  <para>In addition to user-visible improvements, GNOME &version; includes a
  number of improvements to the underlying platform that should be
  appreciated by developers building applications on top of GNOME's powerful
  framework.</para>
  <sect2 id="rngconf">
    <title>GConf</title>
  <para>The GConf daemon now maintains its locks in /tmp by default which
    means GConf will not attempt to contact a daemon on a remote
    machine if the user is using a shared NFS home directory. To use
    the old behavior of maintaining the lock in ~/.gconfd, you can
    set the GCONF_GLOBAL_LOCKS environment variable.</para>
  <para>gconf_entry_copy(), gconf_entry_ref() and gconf_entry_unref()
    added for memory management of GConfEntry. gconf_entry_free() is
    deprecated.</para>
    <para>A number of options have been added to gconftool:
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>--dump and --load to allow the dumping and loading of parts of
        the GConf tree to and from xml. Useful, for making copies of
        your preferences and such.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>--get-type to find out the type of a key</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>--get-list-size and --get-list-element for more fine-grained
        access to lists.</para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>--makefile-uninstall-rule to allow schemas to be
        un-installed.</para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

    </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="rngnomevfs">
    <title>gnome-vfs</title>
    <para>Gnome-vfs includes a number of improvements that may be of interest to
    developers. Gconf keys can now be set to not use the proxy settings for
    some domains/ips. A new uri-scheme, "dav:", has been added,  which behaves
    essentially the same as "http:" but is preferred for referencing webdav
    resources, so those uris will open in the right app and not always
    in the web browser.</para>
    <para>A new "gnome_vfs_url_show()" function has been added to show a uri
    with the default handler for it. This replaces gnome_url_show() in libgnome
    (which now calls the new gnome-vfs function). The new code also looks at the
    mime type of the file, in addition to special-case handlers for some types
    of URIs.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>