<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>
  <sect2 id="rncontrolcenter">
  <title>Control Center</title>

  <sect3 id="rn-controlcenter-keyboard">
  <title>Keyboard Layouts</title>

    <para>GNOME &version; makes it easier to use multiple keyboard layouts. For instance, you might want to change from a U.S.
    English keyboard layout to a Russian keyboard layout, and then back again, to enter one Russian word in the middle of an
    english sentence. This is particularly useful to the millions of people in the world who regularly communicate in more than one
    language. You could click on the Keyboard Indicator panel applet to switch layouts, or you might choose a key combination
    instead, such as pressing both shift keys together.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-keyboardlayouts">
      <title>Keyboard Preferences - Layouts</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;controlpanel-keyboardlayouts.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Layouts tab, in the Keyboard Preferences control panel.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </para>

    <para>GNOME &version; also integrates the multimedia keys into the regular Keyboard
    Shortcuts control panel, making it easy to use your keyboard's special keys to change
    volume or control music or video applications. This functionality was previously in the Acme utility.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-multimediakeys">
     <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
       <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
           <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;controlpanel-keyboardshortcuts.png" format="PNG"/>
           </imageobject>
           <textobject><phrase>The Keyboard Shortcuts control panel.</phrase></textobject>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rn-controlcenter-background">
  <title>Desktop Background</title>

    <para>GNOME &version; has a new easy-to-use Desktop Background control panel, which you can access quickly by
    right-clicking on the desktop. When you add new pictures, it will remember whether each one should be scaled or tiled.

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-background">
     <title>Desktop Background</title>
       <screenshot>
         <mediaobject>
           <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;controlpanel-background.png" format="PNG"/>
           </imageobject>
           <textobject><phrase>The Desktop Background control panel.</phrase></textobject>
         </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </para>

  </sect3>

</sect2>
