<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.8">
]>

<sect2 id="rnplatform">
  <title>Platform Improvements</title>
  <para>In addition to user-visible improvements, GNOME &version; includes a
  number of improvements to the underlying platform that should be
  appreciated by developers building applications on top of GNOME's powerful
  framework.</para>
  
  <sect3 id="rngtk">
    <title>GTK+</title>

    <para>GTK+ 2.4 adds significant new functionality while maintaining source and binary compatibility with GTK+ 2.2.
    Major new features include:

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>New file selector widget, with improved UI, filters, previews, customization, and optional use of the GNOME vfs system.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>New ComboBox widget with improved API, UI, and model/view separation.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>New Expander widget, useful for hiding complex user-interface options.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Action-based toolbar and menu API.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Bidirectional improvements, for languages such as Arabic and Hebrew. GTK+ now automatically determines the direction for widgets based on their contents.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Automatic text completion option for ComboBoxes and Entry widgets.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Speed-optimization option for TreeViews.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>General performance improvements.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    </para>
    
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rngnomevfs">
    <title>gnome-vfs</title>

    <para>The GNOME Virtual File system allows applications to support several protocols and file systems via the same unified API.
    Improvements in GNOME &version; include

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Support for sftp and Windows SMB protocols.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improved authentication, with password keyring storage.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Detection of mounted drives and network volumes.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improved MIME type system, via the freedesktop.org shared standards.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    </para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rngstreamer">
    <title>GStreamer</title>

    <para>The GStreamer multimedia framework is gradually maturing, and is now used by several applications, such as
    Sound Juicer, Rhythmbox, Totem, and Marlin.</para>
    <para>Improvements in GNOME &version; include

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Support for the ALSA sounds drivers used in Linux kernel 2.6.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Support for more formats, and better support for existing formats, including MP3, Ogg/Vorbis, FLAC, Wave, and mod.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Improved error notification.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>Error messages are now translated, so applications can report problems in the user's own language.</para></listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    </para>
    
  </sect3>

</sect2>
