<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.10">
]>
<sect2 id="rnapplets">
  <title>Panel Items</title>

  <para>
   GNOME &version; has had a significant focus on panel items (sometimes
   referred to as applets). Many panel applications have been rewritten in order
   to fully leverage new technology on the desktop, as well as give tighter
   integration with the rest of the desktop.
  </para>

  <para>
   Most applets now support the transparent panel setting that has been
   available in GNOME for a long time. Allowing users to be able to have
   transparent, or translucent panels.
  </para>
 
  <sect3 id="rnapplets-modemlights">
  <title>Integrated Modem Control</title>
  <para>
   A new applet for controlling your Modem debuts in GNOME &version;. This
   monitor integrates with GNOME System Tools to give you a unified method for
   controlling and monitoring the state of your Modem.

   <!-- figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-modemlights">
    FIXME
    <title>The new modem control applet</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-clock+calendar.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The new modem control applet</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure -->
   
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplets-trash">
  <title>Panel Trashcan</title>

  <para>
   Oft requested, GNOME &version; features an optional trashcan for your Panel.
   Just like the trashcan on your desktop, you can drag and drop onto the trash
   to remove files and do other actions. Clicking on the trashcan will allow you
   to view deleted items in Nautilus, or you can simply empty your trash from
   the Panel.

  <!-- figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-networkmonitor">
    FIXME
    <title>Network Monitor - wireless connection</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gnome-netstatus.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The Network Monitor panel applet, showing a wireless connection.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure -->
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplets-drivemount">
  <title>Control Mounted Volumes</title>

  <para>
   In the age of removable, easy to use digital media, we are constantly adding
   and removing volumes from our computer systems. The volume mounter applet
   can help. Integrating into GNOME-VFS, the same interface that Nautilus uses
   to mount and unmount volumes. This application shows you the current user
   mountable (or unmountable) volumes, allowing you to mount them, eject them or
   open them in Nautilus. It is the perfect compliment to Nautilus and the GNOME
   Volume Manager.
   
   <!-- figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-batterymonitor">
    FIXME
    <title>Battery Monitor</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-battstat-applet.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The battery monitor applet.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure -->
  
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplets-gweather">
  <title>Get even more weather</title>
  <para>
   The weather monitor has even more locations then ever before, and our team of
   localisers have worked hard to clean up the weather locations available in
   your area. In addition to this, we have improved the collection of weather
   information and added new weather information, including sunrise and sunset
   calculations for most of our locations.

   <!-- figure id="rnscreenshot-panel-applet-weather">
   FIXME
    <title>Weather Report</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-weather-report.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The weather report applet.</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure -->
   
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplets-mixer">
  <title>Sound control</title>
  <para>
   A new mixer for your panel (combined with a new look mixer on the desktop)
   leaverages the most out of your sound hardware. Using the GStreamer
   multimedia framework (the same framework that powers Totem, Sound Juicer,
   the GNOME CD player and a pantheon of third party applications), the mixer is
   now more flexible and stable then ever before. Additionally, like many
   programs in GNOME &version; the look of the mixer is entirely themable via
   the GNOME icon theme.
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplets-stickynotes">
  <title>Taking note</title>
  <para>
   The ever popular stickynote program, that leaves PostIt style notes on your
   desktop has been improved to offer new features and become aware of your
   different workspaces. Now if you have multiple workspaces, your stickynotes
   will stay where they belong.
  </para>
  <para>
   Stickynotes now also act slightly differently from before. Stickynotes now
   remain on top of the desktop so that you can't lose them. To hide the notes,
   simply click on the icon and select to hide the stickynotes. Now your
   stickynotes will always be where you expect them.
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnapplet-cpufreq">
  <title>Especially for laptops</title>
  <para>
   GNOME now includes something to monitor the speed of your laptop CPU. The CPU
   Frequency Monitor talks to frequency scalable processers (like those with
   Intel Speedstep) to find out how fast they are currently running. It also
   offers a selection of speeds for you to choose between if you don't have
   automatic frequency scaling enabled.
  </para>
  </sect3>

  <para>
   Some applets have gone away in GNOME &version; because they have either been
   replaced by something better, or were unmainted and insecure. The three
   applets to be removed are, the CD Player applet, the standalone wireless
   monitor and mailbox check applet.
  </para>
  <para>
   The CD Player panel applet did not interoperate well with GNOME CD Player,
   instead now inserting a CD will start GNOME CD Player automatically, it can
   then be controlled from the user interface or from a notification icon that
   is placed in your Panel.
  </para>
  <para>
   The standalone wireless applet has now been superseeded by GNOME Netstatus,
   which has had wireless support since GNOME 2.8.
  </para>
  <para>
   The mailbox monitor has been removed because it was unmaintained and
   insecure. We hope to have an solution integrated with Evolution in the
   future. If you don't use Evolution for your mail, you can use a third party
   application such as <link
   href="http://www.nongnu.org/mailnotify/">mailnotify</link>.
  </para>

</sect2>
