
    <title>Metacity Window Manager</title>

    <para>
  GNOME 2.2 officially incorporates the Metacity window manager, a fully 
  integrated window manager that uses GTK+ for UI elements, communicates 
  tightly with the panel and other desktop elements, and is configured straight
  from the GNOME preferences dialogs.
    </para>

    <para>
  At the same time, all interaction between the window manager and the desktop 
  is done via documented standards (see <xref linkend="rnstandards"/>), 
  so you can substitute the window manager of your choice from a long 
  list of available options: Sawfish, fvwm2, icewm, Waimea, Openbox, 
  are just some of them.
    </para>

    <para>
  Early versions of Metacity were in wide use a month or two after GNOME 2.0, 
  so many people will already be familiar with its basic features:
</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Does not expose the concept of "window manager" to the user. 
        For example, keybindings are configured in the GNOME 
        "Keybindings" dialog, theme is configured in the GNOME 
        "Theme" dialog.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Simple XML theme format is designed to allow a single theme
        to work with large and small font sizes, button reordering, 
        and other user preferences. No more editing the theme 
        to change your preferences.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Like all of GNOME, full keyboard navigation, including navigation to the
        panel and the desktop background.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Inherits the standard GTK+ internationalization support.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Uses GTK+ to draw window frames, tracking colors, fonts, and so forth
        from the GTK+ theme. (Colors may not be tracked by all Metacity themes,
        but any Metacity theme can choose to do so.)
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
    

    <para>
  Some new features that may not be in the version of Metacity you've
  tried before:
</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Themeable icons in the window menu.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Handles dynamic resolution changes via Xrandr extension.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Supports keybindings with &lt;Super&gt;, &lt;Hyper&gt; and &lt;Meta&gt; 
        keys. (Including Windows logo key.)
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Supports stay-on-top and stay-below hints.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Allows window buttons to be rearranged (close button on left, etc.), 
        as a user preference, not part of the theme.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Better multihead support.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Startup notification support.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Numerous performance optimizations, especially for high-latency 
        connections.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        Numerous bug fixes and behavior tweaks.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
